# Théo Fuhrmann



# profile

Currently pursuing a master's in **Sound and Music Computing** at Universitat Pompeu Fabra, I bring a solid foundation in **machine learning** and **computer vision** from my previous role at Silt, a digital identification startup. I hold a degree in **Computer Science** from the Polytechnic University of Catalonia (UPC), with a specialization in Artificial Intelligence and algorithms. I have a mix of solid academic training and practical experience, and I enjoy working with others to take on challenging, creative problems.

#### contact

theositges@gmail.com theofuhrmann.github.io Github: theofuhrmann LinkedIn: theofurhmann

### languages

Spanish (native) French (native) Catalan (native) English (C1, fluent)

# programming languages

Python, C, C++, Java, JavaScript, YAML, R, Bash/Zsh

### machine learning

WandB, PyTorch (+ Lightning), Sklearn, Tensorflow, Pandas, Pillow, OpenCV

### back-end

Django, PostgreSQL, REST APIs

# cloud based technologies

AWS, Docker, Firebase

## music

Piano, Ableton

### education

2024-Pres Master's in Sound and Music Computing Universitat Pomeu Fabra (UPF)

2018–2022 **Degree in Computer Science** Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)

Specialization in Computation (AI, algorithms, data science and logic)

2016–2018 **Scientific-Technological Baccalaureate** IES Vinyet, Sitges, Barcelona

With honors

# experience

Oct-Oct 2022-24 Al Specialist in Computer Vision

Silt

• Engineered neural networks using convolutional layers and known backbones with PyTorch and monitored their performances with WandB.

Barcelona, Remote

Barcelona

Developed ML models for multiple identity documents (national IDs, passports, driving licenses, etc.), selfie, and selfie video recognition.

 Generated multiple synthetics datasets (MRZ images, IDs and MRZs with organic overlays, etc.) for data augmentation.

• Improved the accuracy of the previous anti-spoof model by developing an image recapture detector using the aforementioned datasets, while also expanding the spoof categories.

 Performed multiple back-end and MLOps tasks, such as integrating ML/LLM models with the back-end infrastructure and optimizing the company's ML lifecycle.

Feb-July 2022

**Full-Stack Developer** 

Discoverfy - SaaS Company

• Designed and developed brand new front-end and back-end features following Agile and Scrum methodologies.

 Troubleshooted API data, UI, and UX inconsistencies using PostgreSQL, Node.is and React.

• Integrated Shopify installation methods to run the product on the Shopify platform.

• Implemented a new interface for the product's landing page.

June-Dec 2018 **3D Printing Instructor**  Sitges, Barcelona

Sitges PC

• Ran classes on how to use Tinkercad and Slic3r, a 3D modeling software program and a 3D slicing engine, respectively.

Instructed students on the 3D printing process and techniques.

Assembled the communal 3D printing machine.

#### Sep-Jun 2017-18 Certified LEGO Robotics Instructor

St. Pere de Ribes, Barcelona

Temps de lleure

- Created and organized lesson plans on LEGO WeDo 1.0, LEGO WeDo 2.0, and Scratch.
- Taught 6 to 10 year old children how to build and program LEGO robots.
- Engaged students in solving environmental and technological issues through robotics.

# projects

#### **Cybervulnerability Exploitability Classifier** Feb-June 2022

UPC

Final Thesis

Trained various machine learning models with gathered CVE data to predict the potential exploitability of cybervulnerabilities

**Portfolio Website** June 2020

Developed a custom Processing animation

#### February 2019 **Voice-Sex Recognition Classifier**

UPC

Found patterns given various voice features to recognize the sex of the speaker using neural networks and other machine learning models

### extracurricular courses

#### February 2019 **Introduction to Machine Learning**

UPC

Learned how different ML models worked and applied them using Python

and Tensorflow

#### February 2018 **Cybersecurity**

UPC

Learned the main cybersecurity flaws, attack vectors, and how to avoid

them